（春野はるのサクラ）ここじゃないわ
He's not in here.
（うずまきナルト）
ここでもねえってばよ
He's not in here, either!
（サクラ）ここにもいないわ
（ナルト）いったい
どこにいるんだよ
Where the hell... are you?!
（サクラ）私たち
ようやく ここまで来たのよ
We've finally... made it this far!
（ナルト）どこだ！
Where are you...?!
（サクラ）どこにいるの？
Where are you?
（ナルト）サスケ！
Sasuke!
（サクラ）あっ！
あっ
（うちはサスケ）サクラか？
Sakura, huh?
（サクラ）あ…
サ ス ケ 君
Sa...su...ke.
サスケ…
Sasuke...
（サスケ）ナルトか
So it's you, Naruto...?
（サスケ）
親も兄弟もいねえ てめえに
You don't even have parents or siblings...
俺の何が分かるってんだよ
What do you know about me?!
初めから１人きりだったてめえに
You've been alone from the start!
俺の何が分かるってんだ！ ああ？
What do you know about me?! Huh?!
つながりがあるからこそ苦しいんだ
It's having the bond that makes it painful!
全て失うことが どんなもんか
You've no idea what it's like to lose that...!
お前なんかに分かるか！
（ナルト）
ほんとの親子や兄弟なんて
You're right.
I don't know about having real parents or siblings...
確かに俺には分かんねえ
それなら…
If that's the case...
（サスケ）なんでだ ナルト
Why Naruto...?
なんで そこまでして俺なんかに
Why do you go so far for me...?
俺にとっちゃ
やっとできたつながりなんだ
To me, it's a bond... I've finally been able to establish.
だから 俺は
お前を止めるんだってばよ！
That's why I'll stop you!
（ナルト）それなら なんであのとき…
If that's the case, then why didn't you...?
（サスケ）だったら そのつながりを
俺は 断ち切るまでだ！
Then I'll just break that bond!
俺を殺さなかった？
Why didn't you kill me back then?!
それで断ち切ったつもりかよ！
Is that how you wanted to break the bond?!
サスケ！
Sasuke!
（サスケ）簡単な理由だ
The reason's simple...
お前とのつながりを
断ち切れなかったんじゃない
It's not that I couldn't break the bond with you...
（うちはイタチ）お前も 俺と同じ
万華鏡まんげきょう写輪眼しゃりんがんを開眼しうる者
You're one who might be able
to use the same Mangekyo Sharingan as mine...
ただし それには条件がある
However, there is one condition...
最も親しい友を…
You must kill...
殺すことだ
your closest friend.
（サスケ）あいつに聞かされた
やり方に従って
It was just irritating to me.
Obtaining power according to the method I heard about from him.
力を手にするのが
しゃくだっただけだ
お前の命は
You're only alive because of my passing whim.
俺の気まぐれで
助かっただけだということだ
はっ！ いつの間に
When did he...?!
そういや お前には
Come to think of it,
didn't you have a dream of becoming the Hokage...?
火影ほかげになるって
夢があるんじゃなかったのか？
俺を追い回す暇があったら
修業でもしてりゃよかったのに
If you had the time to chase after me,
you should've spent that time training or something...
なあ ナルト
Right... Naruto?
だから今度は 俺のきまぐれで
And that's why this time around...
You'll lose your life...
お前は命を落とすんだぜ
because of my passing whim.
仲間１人救えねえやつが
火影になんてなれるかよ
There's no way a guy who can't even save one friend...
can ever become the Hokage.
そうだろ？ サスケ
Isn't that right... Sasuke?
あっ サスケ君…
Sasuke-kun!
（サスケ）フッ
（九尾きゅうびの狐きつね）ヌフフフ…
ナルトよ
Naruto...
わしとお前の力を
Show him... our... powers.
見せつけてやれ
フハハハ…
どうした？
What's the matter...?
何を躊躇している
Why do you hesitate...?
わしの力が必要なんだろ？
You need my power, don't you?
さあ
Now then...
（九尾の狐）誰を殺したい？
Who do you want to kill...?
分かっているはずだぞ
You should know.
お前は １人では何もできん
That you can't do anything on your own.
seal
封印を完全に解け！
Break the seal completely!
そうすれば お前に
全ての力を託してやる
I'll grant you all of my powers if you do.
ん？
あっ…
どうして
How...?!
（サスケ）今なら見れる
I can see it now...
これが お前の未知の力だったか
So this is your unknown power, huh...?
まさか お前の中に
こんなものがいたとはな
Who would've thought...
you'd have something like this inside of you...
そうか　うちはの者か
I see... So you're an Uchiha...
よく ここまで成長したものだ
My how you've grown...
ナルトの中のわしが
見えるまでになるとはな
To think you'd be able to see me within Naruto...
忌まわしき その写輪眼
That loathsome Sharingan...
呪われた一族の力というわけか
So that's the power of the cursed clan, huh?
（サスケ）
どうやら 写輪眼を見るのは
初めてではないらしいな
It seems that...
...this isn't the first time you've seen the Sharingan.
なら…
Then... you must be the Nine-Tailed Fox, huh...?
お前が九尾の妖狐ようこか
その動力と
That vision, and Chakra more ominous than mine...
わし以上に まがまがしいチャクラ
かつての うちはマダラと同じだな
It's just like... Uchiha Madara, from long ago...
（ナルト）ん… あっ
知るかよ そんなやつ
Hell if I know... that person.
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Homecoming
（木ノ葉丸このはまる）
見つけたか？ コレ
Did you find it?
（ウドン）こちら異常なし
All clear here.
（モエギ）ターゲット捕捉
Target acquired!
（ウドン）
まずいよ 町に入られちゃう
Uh-oh! It'll get into the village!
（木ノ葉丸）絶対 逃がさないんだな
No way will we let it get away!
（女性）ん？
ああっ！
（走る足音）
（女性）ああ…
（木ノ葉丸）ぐえ～
（ウドン･モエギ）うわあ～
（木ノ葉丸）なんだ コレ
What the--?!
（ウドン）どっち行った？
Where'd it go?
（モエギ）あっちよ
That way!
こら！ あんたたち！
Hey, you squirts!
（男性）こら！
Hey!
（ウドン）ごめんなさい！
W-We're sorry!
（女性）何すんのよ！
What're you doing?!
（モエギ）すみませ～ん
Sorry!
（男性）うわ～
（木ノ葉丸）ごめ～ん
Sorry about that.
"Ichiraku Ramen"
（テウチ）ちょっくら
出前行ってくら～
I'm going out for a small delivery.
（木ノ葉丸）うわあ～ どいて！
Whoa! Outta the way!
（走る足音）
（テウチ）ん？
ああ！
うわ～
（木ノ葉丸）ごめん おっちゃん！
Sorry, pops!
こら！ ナルト！
Hey, Naruto!
（木ノ葉丸）エヘヘッ
じゃ なかった
No, I mean...
木ノ葉丸～！
Konohamaru!
（モエギ）木ノ葉丸君
ターゲットを追い詰めたわ
Konohamaru-kun.
We've cornered the target.
（ウドン）急いで！
Hurry up.
逃げられちゃうよ～
It'll get away!
（木ノ葉丸）大丈夫
No problem!
（木ノ葉丸）うわ～ てい
Why you--!
（モエギ･ウドン）木ノ葉丸君
Give it up already!
- Konohamaru-kun!
（木ノ葉丸）捕まえたんだな コレ
I got him!
（ウドン）右耳にリボン
A ribbon on the right ear...
No doubt about it.
間違いありませんね
（モエギ）エビス先生
Ebisu-sensei, we captured
the lost pet target "Dora."
ターゲットの迷子ペット
ドラを捕獲しました
エヘッ 任務完了だ コレ
Heh-heh... Mission complete!
エエエエ…
いや～！
（マダム･しじみ）ああ～
私のかわいいドラちゃん
Oh, my adorable Dora-chan!
死ぬほど心配したのよ
もう どこに行ってたの
I was worried to death about you.
Where were you?
あんなおばちゃんが飼い主なら
俺だって逃げたくなるんだな
I'd want to run away too,
if an old lady like that
were my owner...
（エビス）木ノ葉丸君！
Konohamaru-kun!
（マダム･しじみ）では
報酬は このとおり
All right, here is the reward.
さあさ 帰りましょう ドラちゃん
Now then, let's go home, Dora-chan.
たかが迷子の猫を捕まえるのに
何時間 かかってるんですか？
How many hours did it take
you guys to catch a simple lost cat?!
だって あの猫
すごく すばしっこくて
But that cat was incredibly quick...
すごく逃げ慣れてるみたいで
And he seemed accustomed
to running away...
言い訳 無用！
I don't want to hear
any excuses!
本来なら この程度の任務
A mission like this must be carried out
quickly and properly!
もっと迅速 かつ 適切に
処理しなければなりません
力不足です
You guys are not good enough!
こんなショボい任務じゃ
I can't display my true strength
on a lame mission like this!
俺の本当の力は出せないんだな コレ
ねえ イルカ先生
もっとこう… すごい任務 ないの？
Say, Iruka-sensei.
Don't you have more of
an awesome mission for me?
（うみのイルカ）
あのなあ 木ノ葉丸
Listen... Konohamaru...
木ノ葉丸君
Konohamaru-kun, you guys just
became Genin.
君たちは まだ
下忍げにんになったばかりなのですよ
いきなり そんなすごい任務を
任せられるはずないでしょ
There's no way I can give missions
like that to you right off the bat, right?!
（綱手つなで）当分はＤランク任務だな
It'll be D-rank missions
until further notice.
そんなんじゃ
満足できないんだな コレ
I can't be satisfied with that!
俺 将来
七代目火影になるんだから
After all, in the future
I'm going to become
the Seventh Hokage.
七代目？ 六代目じゃないのか？
Seventh? Not the Sixth?
六代目は ナルト兄ちゃんだから
Naruto Nii-chan's going to be the Sixth.
（エビス）えっ？
（綱手）あっ
うっ
（ウドン）ナルト兄ちゃんか～
Naruto Nii-chan, huh...?
今 どこにいるのかな？
I wonder where he is right now...
きっと すごい忍になって
戻ってくるんだな コレ
I bet he'll return having become
an awesome Shinobi.
俺 信じてるから
I have faith in him!
七代目火影というより
二代目ナルトだな
He's more of a Second Naruto
than a Seventh Hokage...
（イルカ）ナルト
元気でやってるか？
Naruto... Are you holding up okay?
ぜってえ強くなって
サスケを取り戻してやるってばよ
No matter what, I'll get strong
and bring Sasuke back!
（イルカ）そういって
自来也じらいや様と本格的な修業に出て
Quite a bit of time has passed
since he said that
and went off for real training
with Jiraiya-sama...
ずいぶんとたつ
（シズネ）ええ そろそろ里に
戻ってくるころではないでしょうか
Yes. Isn't it just about the time
he should be returning?
戻ってきて
もらわねば困る
We need him to return.
ちかぢか 大きな動きが
あるだろうからな
After all, there will probably be
significant developments sometime soon.
（はがねコテツ）ああ？
（神月かみづきイズモ）ん？
（コテツ）おい
あれ もしかして
Hey... Could that be...?
（イズモ）ああ 間違いない
Yeah... No doubt about it.
（男性）はい いらっしゃいませ～
（木ノ葉丸）サクラ姉ちゃん！
Sakura Nee-chan!
（サクラ）ん？
ああ 木ノ葉丸
Oh, Konohamaru!
どこ行くんだ？ コレ
Where are you off to?
（サクラ）里の正門
The main village gate.
綱手様のお使いで
午前中の通行台帳を回収にね
I have to pick up the morning pedestrian
traffic ledger for Tsunade-sama.
一緒に来る？
You want to come?
（ナルト）２年半ぶりぐらいだってばよ
It's been about two and a half years.
（自来也）そうだの～
Yeah, it has...
（木ノ葉丸）
いきなり めちゃくちゃ
ひっかきやがって あのドラ猫
And then that Dora cat suddenly
starts scratching me like crazy!
（サクラ）ウフフッ
あった あった そんな任務
We had missions like that, too.
It kind of takes me back.
なんか懐かし～
そういえば ナルト兄ちゃんから
何か連絡あったか？ コレ
Come to think of it,
have you heard anything
from Naruto Nii-chan?!
（サクラ）まだ なんにも
Nothing... yet.
そっか
I see...
そろそろ帰ってくる
はずなんだけどね
He should be coming back soon, though...
こんにちは
イズモさん コテツさん
Hello, Izumo-san, Kotetsu-san.
（コテツ）おお 来た来た
Oh, look who's here...
（サクラ･木ノ葉丸）ん？
（コテツ）町のほうに行ってみな
Why don't you head on into town?
（イズモ）おもしろいものが見られるぞ
You'll see something interesting.
（木ノ葉丸）おもしろいもの？
Something interesting...?
（サクラ）あっ…
まさか
Don't tell me!
（ナルト）よっ
ヘっ
へっ… はっ！
（自来也）ふふふ～ん
はしゃぎよって
He's having a ball...
（ナルト）えいっ
なっつかし～
This takes me back!
The village hasn't changed a bit!
全然 変わってねえってばよ～
みんな～！ うずまきナルトが…
Everyone! Uzumaki Naruto's back!
帰ってきたぞ！
（ナルト）何もかも
懐かしいってばよ
It's all so nostalgic...!
うん うん
Yup! Yup!
あっ…
ハハッ
綱手のばあちゃんの顔岩が
増えてやんの
They added Granny Tsunade's
Mountainside Image!
（サクラ）あ… ほんとに？
For real...?
ほんとだ！
For real!
（サクラ）ナルト？
Naruto? Is that you, Naruto?
ナルトなの？
（ナルト）ん？
（サクラ）いつ帰ってきたのよ ナルト
When did you get back, Naruto?!
（ナルト）たった今 だってばよ！
Just now!
久しぶり サクラちゃん
Long time no see, Sakura-chan!
ヘッ へへへ
（サクラ）ああ…
あんた 私より
背 高くなったんじゃない？
You've gotten taller than me,
haven't you?
（ナルト）ん？
Huh...?
あ… ほんとだ
Oh! You're right.
（サクラ）なんか 見ない間に
ずいぶん たくましくなっちゃって
He kind of... got
a build since I saw him last...
どう？ 私 少しは
女らしくなっちゃった？
So? You think I've become
a bit womanly?
大丈夫
全然 変わってないってばよ
You're fine!
You haven't changed a bit.
（サクラ）え…
ふんっ！
（ナルト）あら？
（自来也）
お前は 女心っちゅうもんが
分かっとらんの～
You just don't understand
the heart of a woman...
（木ノ葉丸）ナルトの兄ちゃん！
Naruto Nii-chan!
（ナルト）ん？
（木ノ葉丸）お色気の術
Sexy Jutsu!
（自来也）うわ～！
Ohh!
（サクラ）な…
Wha--?!
どうだ？ コレ
How about that?!
Pretty nice waist, hips and bust, huh?!
かなりの ボン キュッ ボン だろ？
（ナルト）なっ ハハハ…
（木ノ葉丸）あ？
木ノ葉丸
Konohamaru...
I'm not a kid anymore.
俺ってば もう ガキじゃないんだ
お前も そんな術をやってるようじゃ
ダメだってばよ
And you too, shouldn't be using Jutsu...
like that...
（木ノ葉丸）ん…
（サクラ）そうだよね
That's right. It isn't just
your appearance that's matured...
成長したのは
見た目だけじゃないよね
なんか 少し寂しい気もするけど
I kind of feel a bit lonesome,
but you've turned out quite admirable,
haven't you, Naruto?
立派になったね ナルト
あんたのことだから
Knowing you, I bet you came back
having acquired some incredible Jutsu.
きっと すごい術
身につけて帰ってきたんだろうな
そんな術では
なまぬるいってばよ！
That's such a boring Jutsu!
見よ！ 新開発した
俺の新エロ忍術！
Check out my freshly
developed New Pervy Ninjutsu!
（サクラ）そうそう
新エロ忍術とか
Right... Like the New Pervy Ninjutsu...
（ナルト）いくぞ～！
Here we go!
（サクラ）って このバカ～！
Hey, you idiot!
（サクラ）うう…
ふん…
ええい…
中身は全く成長しとらんのか おのれは！
You haven't changed at all,
have you, you jerk?!
何年かぶりに会って
After seeing each other for
the first time in like two years!
たった２分ちょいで
ツッコミ入れさせんな コラ～！
You make me do this
in barely two minutes!
さっきは お前に キラキラ乙女心は
どこに持ってきゃいいんだ！
What am I supposed to do
with the feelings of admiration
I had for you earlier, huh?!
ああ？
（自来也）
あのキレ具合と あの怪力
- That short temper and incredible strength.
- I'm not the least bit lonesome!
まるで 綱手２世じゃのう
- She's a second-generation Tsunade.
- Huh? God, I'm mad at myself!
（ナルト）やっぱ
サクラちゃん 変わってない
Just like I thought,
Sakura-chan hasn't changed at all...
っつうか
前より凶暴になった気が…
In fact, I get the feeling she's
even more vicious than before...
（サクラ）ああ？ なんか言ったか？
Huh? Did you say something?
（綱手）久しぶりだな ２人とも
It's been a long time, you two.
修業の成果はあったんだろうな
I'm sure your training produced
good results, right?
（自来也）なんの成果もなしに
戻ってきたとでも思っとるのか？
Do you think we came back
without making progress?
（ナルト）バッチリだってばよ
It went perfectly!
（綱手）では 早速
成果を見せてもらおう
Then show me those
results immediately.
（ナルト）見せるって…
Show you...?
（綱手）ある男の相手をしてもらう
You will take on a particular man.
このために わざわざ
ここ数日は任務にもつけず
I didn't send him on any missions
for the past several days
待機してもらっていたのだ
and had him standby
for this very purpose.
その相手とは…
Your opponent will be...
（綱手）入れ！
Come in!
ああ～！
Oh!
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
本日 午後５時ごろ
砂隠れの里のとりでにて
Today at around five
in the afternoon,
Security Ninja were found collapsed
警邏けいら忍者たちが
倒されているのが発見された
at the fortress of
the Village Hidden in the Sand.
忍たちに
争った形跡が見られないことから
No signs of dispute were found
within the scene of the crime;
犯行は顔見知りによるものか
あるいは
leading officials to believe
the crime might have been committed
手練てだれの侵入者によるものと
見られている
by someone in the village,
or a skilled intruder.
また 同じころ
赤い雲の模様が入った...
Around the same time,
there have been reported sightings
黒い衣に身を包んだ２人組の
目撃情報があり
of two men dressed in black clothing
with red cloud patterns.
事件との関連が予想される
They are likely connected
to the incident.
次回「暁あかつき、始動」
Next time: "The Akatsuki Makes Its Move"
The
Akatsuki
Makes Its
Move
Leaf Village
Sightseeing
Society
（ナルト）木ノ葉 観光協会
Society for Leaf Tourism.
よく来たな
Glad you came!
俺様が 木ノ葉隠れの里の
とっておきスポットを紹介してやるぜ
I'll introduce you to some of
the best spots in the Leaf Village!
まずは
木ノ葉といったら これ
First off, speaking of the Leaf,
there's this village symbol
歴代の火影が刻まれている
里の象徴 顔岩
with the line of previous
Hokages carved into it,
the “Mountainside Images”.
First Hokage
Going from the left,
左から
木ノ葉隠れの里をつくった
木遁もくとん忍術を操る初代
there's the First Hokage who built the
Leaf Village and uses the Wood Style Ninjutsu.
Second Hokage
断トツの戦闘能力で
Then there's the Second Hokage who has incredible
battle skills and uses the Water Style Ninjutsu.
水遁すいとん忍術を操る二代目
それから
Third Hokage
Next,
いつも俺たちのことを
見守ってくれてた
the one who always watched over us.
The old grandpa, Third Hokage.
三代目のじいちゃん
俺の体に 九尾の化け狐を封じた
There's the one who who sealed the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit inside me.
四代目
the Fourth.
Fourth Hokage
そんで 現在の五代目火影
And then, there's
the Fifth and current Hokage,
綱手のばあちゃん
Granny Tsunade.
Fifth Hokage
ボン キュッ ボ～ン の
ナイスバディ
She's got a slamming nice body!
医療忍術を極める伝説のくノ一
She's the legendary Kunoichi who's a master of Medical Ninjutsu!
でも～ 若作りしてっけど
実は 50過ぎてる…
However, she dresses younger than she really is.
As it happens, she's fift-
（殴る音）
（ナルト）うぎゃ
To be
continued...